#### Vini Anand

## Program Management | Cloud Transformation and Transition | Delivery

Mobile: +91 9113818327 | Email: viniana@gmail.com

LinkedIn Profile: https://www.linkedin.com/in/vini-anand-78a817210/

### **Professional Summary**

Solution driven and proven experience as Program Manager with 17 Years of overall experience with 14+ years into Project Management/Program Management/Consulting roles, licensed professional with PRINCE2® Foundation and Agile® Practitioner, Azure fundamentals certificate, helped many customers realize their cloud value through an optimized, governed, and measured roadmap, seeking opportunity to practice my business understanding, strong stakeholder management, problem solving skills, technical and professional practices, customer focused approach, driving decisions and negotiation skills to accelerate deployments and boost company's profitability significantly.

#### **Employment History**

Program Manager, Cloud Product Engineering, Trianz Digital Consulting Private Ltd.

November 2022 – Present

- Solutioned, strategized and delivered a highly automated SaaS based cloud migration platform which targeted and resolved one of the biggest industry problems of low speed and high cost of migration. Platform build with PostgreSQL as its relation Database, using cloud APIs with a self-guided user interface, using Hashicorp vault and AWS secret managers and appropriate Identity and access controls in place.
- Successful planning, execution and delivery of critical edge scenarios like ON-Prem to any cloud, AWS to AWS, AWS to Azure, Azure to Azure and Azure to AWS, On-Prem to GCP.
- Design RFPs/SOWs. work closely with application owners, cloud architects, DevOps teams, Pre-sales, Business development teams, client success managers, Project Sponsors, CTOs and Business users to collaborate, design and review solutions to derive the maximum business value.
- Review "R" strategy for migrations and analyse the risk and cost factors associated. Categorize the applications based on their complexity, resistance over downtime tolerance, vendor support restrictions and resource utilization. Define and implement the overall strategic direction of the program while focusing the long-term business strategies to achieve set targets.
- Managing and leading a high performing teams, work with developers and technology partners to drive product deliverables.
   Collaborate across workstream owners, product engineering, platform and other Business functions and diligently coordinating to solve problems, find solution, drive changes.
- Review solution architecture diagrams and create technical specs based up on the client requirements and implement end to end cloud solutions for business applications and hosted infrastructure.
- Develop plans and ensure successful execution of projects. Monitoring and analysing usage patterns, draw conclusions, and
  provide recommendations based on the outcome. Methodical analysis helps to identify new opportunities and to mitigate any
  potential risks through industry and market changes.

# Program Manager, Cognizant, Bangalore

March 2022 – November 2022

- Transition, Transformation and Modernization of the customer's current IT infrastructure and Applications.
- Collaborate and interview key stakeholders to review business requirements. Presentation to potential application owners, domain architects, cloud architects and project stakeholders to align with the migration approach.
- Use data analysis approach to generate insights and publish dashboards for strategic decision making to approach business users and help them adapt and cooperate with the transition plan. Track budgets, resource allocations, Control changes or contract deviations and smooth transition.
- Design and execute various Workstreams to structure the delivery approach which includes building cloud landing zones, infrastructure and application Migration, Network transformation projects, security upgrades, Azure Privilege Identify Manager deployment, Azure MFA deployment, Service now integration for Event management, Azure defender, Azure Sentinel, Service desk process changes, overall ITSM process and change management.
- Conduct design review calls to review and agree on functional, non-functional requirements, naming conventions, in-scope, out of scope components, DR and Backup strategies, platform Automation requirements, any third party or vendor dependencies, architectural design decisions, risks in High-level and low-level designs.
- Follow a structured program governance model, Monthly presentation to Steering Committee to share the programme performance per workstream, highlight any dependencies, discuss RAID logs, discuss any service improvement roadmaps,

demand/capacity management, discuss any compliance and security audit schedules, Discuss and agree upon the exit criteria for the overall program and the toll-gate criteria for each wave.

#### Sr. Project Manager, Sungard Availability Services Ltd, Bangalore

April 2016 - March 2022

- Worked on fast-paced project execution environment, a mix of Agile and Waterfall.
- Worked on early engagements where focus is to accelerate the solution delivery and better customer experience by engaging
  the key stakeholders like solution architects, engineering leads, project managers to assess the customer requirements and
  assist the contract team right sizing the resources and efforts. Worked closely with sales and presales teams to evaluate and
  design elements to ensure competitive MRR (Monthly Recurring Cost).
- Assess business implications for each project phase and track progress to meet deadlines, and cost targets. Develop detailed program/project execution plan and managed all implementation processes including resource allocation, progress tracking, monitoring change control process, testing, documentation.
- Identifying Risks, Categorizing, documenting, communicating, and preparing the Mitigation Plan. Handle procurement requests, Work with vendors for quotations, Release POs and track shipment. Work with Data Center Operations team for shipping, receiving devices and appliances, for Hands & Feet Support, DC deployments, cabling, fetching Rack Elevations, Cable maps, cross connects, Fiber extensions etc.
- Handle weekly project Status calls with customer and engineering, Discuss the Open action Items and dependencies. Share
  weekly dashboards with customer and leadership for Critical Projects. Ensure all project documentations are well maintained
  throughout the project life-cycle. Risks, assumptions, and constraints are well documented. Knowledge base is updated.
- Review Net Promoter Scores and work on the gaps as needed.

### Project Management Lead, Mphasis Ltd, Bangalore

May 2011 - April 2016

- Review Project quotes, deliverables, technical resources to be involved and Team Sizing Documents. Attend quote review calls
  and suggest required man hours, technical resources required to support the solution, finalize, and send it for customer
  approvals.
- Experience in Project reporting and tracking tools like Aldea, LPMO, PPMC, MSPS (HP).
- Initiate Project Kick-Off Meeting Including Business and Project Teams. Drive project checkpoint calls and ensure project ontime delivery. For any deviation, highlight underlying issues and Risks to the stakeholders and ensure timely resolution.
- Work closely with Solution Architects, DC site support personnel, DC cabling teams, Network Engineers, SAs, SAN Ops,
  Active directory Teams, Load Balancing teams, Application Teams, System security Teams, Tool's scanning & Monitoring
  team, VMware teams, Logistics vendors, Billing teams, to deliver the project ensuring quality. Present project expense Vs
  revenue forecasting and calculating the monthly Cost Margin Estimates.
- Project status review with client on weekly basis. Sharing the project progress status.
- Submitting RFCs in the HPSM tool and getting it through the CAB meetings for implementation approvals.
- Planning the cutovers for server rebuilders, Move to production activities, new server builds, Complete Data center Migrations, OS / SW / infrastructure upgrades. Database migrations.
- Submit the project for invoicing capturing every deliverable including Man time efforts and bill that to the client.

### Backup Administrator, IBM India Ltd, Chennai

June 2009 – May 2011

• Provided comprehensive training to internal and off-site users to optimize systems maintenance and resolve recurring issues. Created nightly jobs for database backups. Configured and tested Windows Server operating systems with roles features. Contributed to development, administration and testing of disaster recovery plans. Conducted routine and emergency maintenance of assigned data centre equipment. Maintained current software licenses for computers and mobile devices. Performed software installations and upgrades to UNIX or Windows operating systems. Supported day-to-day operations, monitoring and resolving client/server and storage issues. Delivered Tier 2 and Tier 3 support for problem identification, diagnosis and issue resolution. Attended meetings to deliver status reports to key stakeholders.

#### System Analyst, Satyam Computer Services Ltd, Chennai

September 2006 – June 2009

Worked for a banking Client to implement Core Banking Solutions, Disaster Recovery solution and Data Centre build projects,
Help Desk and NOC builds. Designed proactive preventive maintenance schedules to prevent unnecessary downtime and
hardware faults. Installed important security and functionality patches to maintain optimal protections against intrusion and

system reliability. Monitored temperature and power draw to immediately detect faults and failures. Oversaw file system and storage upgrades while safeguarding data integrity and redundancy.

#### Qualification

 Bachelor of Computer Applications, Major in Mathematics and Data Science, Teerthankar Mahaveer Institute of Management and Technology, 2006, Aggregate 85%

#### Licenses

• PRINCE2® Foundation and Agile® Practitioner | Certified Scrum master (CSM) | Azure Fundamentals and concepts | IBM System p Administrator | IBM TSM Backup Admin | ITIL 4 foundation Certification

#### Skills

- Program Management and Governance into IT Infrastructure transition and cloud transformation
- Monitoring and Tracking KPI matrices
- Experience working with Pre-sales, solutioning, Cost and budgeting
- Business Process Improvement
- Cross-functional Team Leadership
- Operations Management
- Risk Management
- Customer Relationship Management
- Vendor Management
- Experience with public cloud providers Azure and AWS.
- Private cloud solution on Dell's Vxrail platform and ESC
- Working experience on Microsoft Projects and Visio
- Working experience on projects using Agile methodologies and waterfall methodologies
- Data Analytical Skills- knowledge on Business Analysis with Excel, R, Power BI, SQL
- Hands-on experience on Service Now ticketing tool and JIRA
- Great Presentation and articulation skills
- Lead, Coach, People Management with operational efficiency. ITIL certified, Six Sigma trained

#### Key Projects and Programs handled

- Cloud Transformation, Modernization and Transition: Planning and execution of On-prem to Azure migration of business-critical Applications, hosted on hyper-V and ESXi hosts. Transform to Azure Monitor, Azure Sentinel, Azure Active Directory, ZScaler Deployment, Microsoft Defender deployment for end points. ServiceNow ITOM deployment, ITSM process and procedures upgrade and transitioning to BAU, training. Governance and Risk Management. DC exit.
- Cloud Automation Product Engineering: Product roadmap creation, development of highly automated hybrid/any cloud
  to any cloud migration product to migration SAP and NON-SAP Workloads and application dependencies. Creating CMDB
  transformation mappings, Leading the product engineering team of UI/UX developers, Microservices, Platform, Ansible
  team, QAs, Marketing. Map activities within the SDLC lifecycle. Plan and execute POCs and Pilots. Security compliance,
  Internal VAPT and cloud coverage reports review and validation.
- **Cloud Migration product Content writing**: Developing the Cloud migration product training modules with technical depth for organization wide podcast and for external audience. Team of 5 individuals from Learning and development team.
- Private and Public Cloud Migration Program for managed customers: Managed Services Client migrations to AWS, Cloud
  Recovery solutions for Virtual Servers, Infra refresh projects, On-Prem to Azure, ECS to cloud, ECS to private cloud migration
  on VxRail platform
- Recovery to Cloud solution deployment: Implement Recovery to Cloud solutions, DRaaS using data mover software like Zerto, CCL BIPS
- Infrastructure Security Refresh projects: Deployment of SIEM, IDS/IPS log management tools, Network Intrusion Protection, Unified threat Management, Vulnerability Scanning
- Datacenter relocation and build: Plan and execute datacenter relocation and build. Deploying Circuits, POTs line, long lines, Internet Links, Intranet links, AS Wave, AS connect Plus, AS ethernet. Complex Structured Cabling, Conduiting, MMF, SMF, SC, LC, Cross Connect. Work with Telco vendors: CenturyLink/Level3, Zayo, AT&T, Verizon.
- QA automation and Artifacts auditing: Lead, Planned and executed the QA automation program across the practices.